NIKUNJ JADHAV

nikunjjadhav786@gmail.com | +91 9619073067 | Github/Nixk01 | linkedin/nikunj-jadhav

Profile

A Cloud Associate with 1.5 years of expertise in migrating on-premise servers into cloud architecture by using AWS and Azure. Proactive and committed to solving real-world problems, through improvising old procedures & creating new uses-cases.

Work Experience

Cloud Associate April 2022 - August 2023

SaphhireInfoTech Ventures Pvt. Ltd, Mumbai

- Worked as an Cloud Associate, creating daily reports & handling client mails & processing the request from Basic to Advance.
- Deployment of Live servers as per client needs, from on-premises network to cloud migration, DR for clients.
- Technology Used: -Azure, VM, Storage, S2S & more. AWS Services Like EC2, S3, Cloudwatch, VPC, Lambda, IAM etc.

Software Intern February 2022 - April 2022

Synergy Technology, Mumbai

- Designed CRUD app with Admin Login & phpMyAdmin Database used with Foreign Key Tables.
- Designed & added Plugin in WordPress.
- Languages & Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHPMyAdmin, PHP 7, Yii2, WordPress

Web-Development Intern

February 2019 - March 2019

Sahu Technologies, Mumbai

- Designed Dynamic UI pages, for Hotel management system and Library Management Systems
- Created a multi-page interactive website, linked it to database and deployed it using PHPMyAdmin
- Languages used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHPMyAdmin

Skills

- Programming Languages: C++, Java, Python.
- Advance Microsoft Excel: VBA, Macros and Dashboards
- Databases: MySQL, SQL Services (SSIS, SSRS), phpMyAdmin
- Visualization Tools: Tableau, PowerBI
- Version Control: Git, GitHub
- Web Development: HTML5, CSS3, PHP, Yii2
- Deep Learning Frameworks: Tensorflow.js
- Python Libraries: Numpy, Pandas, Seaborn, Matplotlib
- Cloud Providers: AWS, Azure
- Proficient with Microsoft tools- Outlook, Excel, PowerPoint, Word
- Soft Skills ProActiveness, Listening, Tasks deadlines

Education

Bachelors of Science in Information Technology (BSc-IT), Mumbai University

2019 - 2021

• CGPA: 7.83/10

Diploma in Computer Science, Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education (MSBTE)

2016 - 2019

73%

Certifications

- Version Control System Git | Coursera
- Data Visualization Tableau, Power-BI | Udemy
- Data Science Bootcamp | Dphi
- Pytorch-Deep learning | Dphi
- Data Analysis with Python | Dphi
- Azure Fundamentals

Projects

Yoga Plus - IIT Bombay's EdTech Hackathon

- Developed an Android app which provides assistance to user to perform yoga and do workouts
- Developed using: Android, Flutter, Tensorflow Lite, Firebase
- Project Link: Yoga Plus

Smart Fit Assistant

- Developed a web app which recognises yoga pose that a user is performing
- Web app uses webcam to capture image and infers pose using MAX deep learning model
- Tools used: HTML, CSS3, Javascript, Tensorflow.js, PoseNet, Model Asset Exchange
- Project Link: Smart Fit Assistant

SOS-Android App

- Developed an android app that trigger SOS via handset buttons without touching the phone screen
- It uses voice recognition to send messages when a certain word is pronounced. Also sends live location along with text messages
- Developed Using Java, Android Studio, XML, JDBC
- Project Link: SOS-Android App

Achievements

- Stood 7th in IIT Bombay EdTech Hackathon
- Stood 3rd in Apscript Hackathon

Volunteering

• Youth Volunteer at HariPrabodham

2017-Present